Hello.
In this lecture, we're going to go over how to set up a Scantron character so it can move around our
level to get started.
If you go over to your Scantron blueprint, open it up and just select the sprite just so that we can
visually see our Scantron when we place it in the level on the source flipbook, select the Scranton
Idol.
And scalpels can turn to bits.
This capsule collision.
I'm just going to adjust my capsule so it fits my skeleton a bit better.
Once you found the correct capsule and size for your skeleton, go to the animation component and just
let the scan turn animation blueprint that we made earlier.
So now we're ready to set up the blueprint logic for Scampton.
If we head over to the event graph.
In some free space.
We just want the right click and therefore add custom event and call this handle different.
So we're going to use some nodes which will handle all the movement force counting character.
So the first thing we want to do, if this is a struggle here and look for add movement input.
Under wild auction, we put a value of one because like I mentioned earlier in our two D game, everything
is going to be in the x axis.
Here on the scale value is going to determine whether our Sandton will move positively in the x axis
or negatively in the x axis.
We're going to use a variable to control this.
So if we just right click promote this to a variable and call this movement direction.
Just good compile.
And for the time being, leave this at one and often event tick to struggle fair and look for handled
movement.
I want you to just select this movement direction and go instant edit so we can edit it whilst inside
of our game.
So now if I can compile and if I just drag my scantron into my level, it should move positively in
the x axis.
So just so that we can test that this all works.
I'm going to drag in my Scantron.
And I'm going to go to simulate and this will simulate my game running.
So now if I go play, we can see my Stanton will quickly move towards the right.
I'm just going to close this, select my Stanton and go to details.
Although at this time I am going to make the movement direction minus one.
And then we must come from here and go assimilate, and then we'll move backwards.
So you have notice my Scantron isn't facing the correct action when it's moving backwards, so we need
to write some blueprint code to fix that.
If we head back to our account.
And BP.
Speaking of right click and make another customer again.
So we just look for add custom event and call this handle rotation.
And if we just drag in the movement direction variable and just get it, if this value is ever greater
than zero, that means the direction must be one.
And that means my character must be moving positively in the x axis.
If that is true, then we're going to make our player character face towards the right.
So to do that, we can just drag okay and look for Branch and hook up from here to here and off of True,
which is on the right click and offset actor rotation.
And I've got two two here in X, Y and Z.
We're going to leave all these values at zero because currently they're zero and my character is facing
towards the right.
If this condition is ever false, that means my character must be moving towards the left.
And if that is true, then we'll make our character face the left.
So we'll just copy this, paste it here.
Although this time in the Z, we don't have a value of 180 because if I go to the people, slap my sprite
and have a value of 180, that means my character is facing towards the left.
So we can just change this back to zero.
I'll compile and save this If I now close this and to test this out, my direction is minus one and
I go simulate.
Whoops.
I actually got to hook this all up.
So.
We just want to drag up here and look for handle.
Rotation.
And now, if I could compile and test this out, my character should face towards the left when they're
moving towards the left.
So similarly, my character is moving towards the left.
If I make this very one, my character should move towards the right.
Nice.
So that's all working.